Guide to the Duke University College Republicans records, 1965-1984
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University College Republicans records 1965-1984
Duke University College Republicans
0.4 linear feet Extent: 400 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Duke University College Republicans, an umbrella organization for all Republicans on campus, was established around 1965. The College Republicans support Republican campaigns at the local, state and national level. Major subjects included are: student activism at Duke University and in North Carolina, the North Carolina Federation of College Republicans, Duke University President Terry Sanford and the International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation controversy, campaign support for Republican candidates, and the general governance of the Duke University College Republicans. Types of materials included are advertisements, clippings, newsletters, meeting minutes and agendas, flyers, correspondence, and miscellaneous writings. The materials in this collection documents the activities of the Duke University College Republicans from about 1965 to 1977. The bulk of the material is from 1973 to 1977. English.
UA.31.08.0002
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
No restrictions.
Provenance
Transfer; 1975; 75-65.
Gift; 1975; 77-55.
Historical Note
The Duke University College Republicans, an umbrella organization for all Republicans on campus, was established around 1965. The College Republicans support Republican campaigns at the local, state and national level. Some of the major events in the club's history are: supporting a four-year medical school at Eastern Carolina University (1974), opposing public financing for election campaigns, hosting North Carolina Federation of College Republican conventions and Republican Party speakers, holding voter registration drives, and writing general position papers and editorials on world political issues and events.
Collection Overview
Contains materials documenting the activities of the Duke University College Republicans, an umbrella organization for all Republicans on campus. Collection includes budgets and yearly reports, clippings from campus events, constitution and bylaws, correspondence, notes from committee meetings, flyers, newsletters, membership lists, and miscellaneous writings concerning Duke University President Terry Sanford. Materials range in date from 1965-1977 (bulk 1973-1977).
Subject Headings
College Republican National Committee (U.S.); College students -- Political activity -- United States; Duke University College Republicans; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity; International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation; North Carolina Federation of College Republicans; Political campaigns -- North Carolina; Political campaigns -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Republican Party (N.C.); Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Sanford, Terry, 1917-; Student movements -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Budgets and reports, 1965-1977 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1974-1985 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1984 (Box 1)
  - North Carolina Federation of College Republicans
    - Conventions, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, meetings and agendas, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
    - New Southerner, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1968-1984 (Box 1)
  - College Republicans newsletter, Duke University, 1966, 1973-1978 (Box 1)
  - Officer and membership lists, 1967-1977 (Box 1)
  - President Terry Sanford and the International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation (ITT) controversy, 1977 (Box 1)
Related Material
School of Law records.
University Archives, Duke University.